Hi there.
Welcome to this video
where we are going to learn about
what it means to be resilient
in digital environments.
The goal of the video is to help you
to understand what resilience is,
and things that you can do
to help yourself to become
more resilient in digital environments.
In the video, firstly, we will
look at what we mean by resilience.
Then we will look at things
we can do to help us
to become more resilient.
According to the dictionary,
resilience is the ability to cope
when exposed to challenges
or things that cause you to feel stressed.
Resilience allows people to bounce back
by adapting to stress in healthy way.
The digital world
can sometimes expose us to a number
of challenges, such as negative
or hateful comments, identity
theft and fraud, and exclusion
by others on social media.
This can leave us feeling sad, anxious,
angry, or a lot of different emotions.
We may also feel a bit powerless
and not know what to do.
Sometimes we may be able to handle
the challenges we face by being resilient.
Resilience is a skill, and we can learn
how to be resilient and bounce
forward from these challenges.
Get up.
Learn from what you have
experienced and move forwards.
Step one:
Acknowledging the challenge
and or stressor and use
problem solving techniques
to resolve the issue.
It shows wisdom to acknowledge
that there is a challenge.
This is a good starting point
to solving the challenge.
Step two: Seeking support to gain
an alternative viewpoint on the issue.
You can sometimes solve
challenges on your own.
Other times, it can be wise to accept
that you need help and to ask for help.
We can chat to someone we trust
like a parent or a teacher for help.
Or call a trusted
kid's helpline for a chat.
Step three: Implementing
self-care strategies.
Sometimes you can find small things
that help you to calm your thoughts and feelings.
This can help you think
more clearly and be more resilient.
These are called coping strategies
or self-care strategies.
It is wise to know what is helpful to you.
What little things help you feel calmer?
Some examples of things
that people do to help them to cope
and care for themselves
when facing challenges are activities
with others such as playing
sport, dancing, helping someone, singing.
Some activities can also
be done alone, such as drawing,
slow breathing, spending time with a pet,
listening to music, reading a book,
writing a journal, gaming.
Step four: Gain sufficient
distance from the problem
to alleviate some of the pressure.
Sometimes it can be wise to take
a break and do something that you enjoy.
This can help you to get some distance
from the challenge you are facing.
It can give you a new perspective
and help you to feel better.
Step five recognize that everyone
makes mistakes in the digital environment.
So next time you feel sad
because somebody says something
mean to you in a group chat,
or when you share something by mistake.
Remember these coping strategies
reflect over the challenging situation.
Is there something that you can learn
from the situation?
Is there something positive
that you can take from the experience
that may help you
or someone else in the future?
So in this short video,
we learned what we mean by resilience
and looked at things we can do
to help us to become more resilient.
Thank you for watching.
Do not forget to watch
other videos in our series.